U.S. Emergency Board No. 118 Records 5045
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 118 Records
1945-1956
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5045
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Transcripts of proceedings and exhibits of the Emergency Board No. 118, 1957. Wage, benefits and work rules case. Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company, Toledo Lakefront Dock Company, and Cleveland Stevedore Company vs. United Mine Workers of America, District 50, 1945-1957.
3114455
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 10, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Mine Workers, on November 30, 1956, requested a modification of its current agreement with the companies, and submitted twenty proposals. Negotiations began and the companies submitted five counter proposals. The services of the National Mediation Board were requested on February 5, 1957 and mediation continued until March 22 without any success, The Mediation Board suggested arbitration, which the union rejected.
On May 9, 1957 the President of the United Statesappointed an emergency board consisting of Nathan Cayton, Dudley E. Whiting and Morrison Handsaker. Hearings wereheld and the Board visited and inspected the docks of two of the companies. Wages, fringe benefits, working rulesand grievances were among the twenty-five issues involved. The Board's report was prepared in three parts, since some recommendations applied to all three companies and some did no and issued on June 7. 1957.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5006: U.S. Emergency Board No. 174 Records 5007: U.S. Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5027: U.S. Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts 5030: U.S. Emergency Board No. 179 Exhibits and Related Material 5036: U.S. Emergency Boards under the Railway Labor Act Reports 5037: U.S. Emergency Board No. 81 Records 5038: U.S. Emergency Board No. 94 Records 5039: U.S. Emergency Board No. 98 Records 5040: U.S. Emergency Board No. 106 Records 5042: U.S. Emergency Board No. 111 Records 5043: U.S. Emergency Board No. 114 Records 5044: U.S. Emergency Board No. 116 Reports and Exhibits 5046: U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records 5047: U.S. Emergency Board No. 120 Records 5048: U.S. Emergency Board No. 121 Records 5050: U.S. Emergency Board No. 124 Records 5051: U.S. Emergency Board No. 125 Records 5052: U.S. Emergency Board No. 129 Records 5053: U.S. Emergency Board No. 130 Records 5054: U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits 5055: U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records 5056: U.S. Emergency Board No. 135 Records 5057: U.S. Emergency Board No. 137 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5058: U.S. Emergency Board No. 138 Records 5059: U.S. Emergency Board No. 142 Records 5060: U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records 5061: U.S. Emergency Board No. 146 Records 5062: U.S. Emergency Board No. 154 Records 5064: U.S. Emergency Board No. 169 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5075: U.S. Emergency Board under the Taft Hartley Act Records 5579: National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists 5934: Arthur Stark Papers on the President's Emergency Board #219
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; United States. Emergency Board No. 118; United Mine Workers of America. District 50
3114455
- Transcripts and Exhibits (Box 1)
  - Transcripts Volumes 1-5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Company Exhibit - Brief on behalf of The Toledo Lakefront Dock Company (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - Ore and coal dock workers hourly wage rates, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents
    December 31, 1956.
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - Earning Statistics, Various Industries, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - The Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - Earning Record - Longshoremen, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - The Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - Average Daily Overtime, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - Consumers' Price Index (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - The Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - Average Annual Earnings (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - The Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - Percentage of Increase Hourly Rates of Pay - Toledo Dock (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - The Toledo Lakefront Dock Company, Toledo, Ohio - Crew Cost Per Hour (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Exhibit of Toledo Lakefront Dock Company - Trundle Engineering report, Job Evaluation Study (missing) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brief on behalf of The Toledo, Lorain, and Fairport Dock Company - Lorain Dock (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Exhibit of the Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company. Lorain, Ohio - The Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company, Lorain, Ohio - Employees' Earning Summary (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Exhibit of the Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company. Lorain, Ohio - The Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company, Lorain, Ohio - Daily Overtime - Lorain Dock (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Exhibit of the Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company. Lorain, Ohio - Consumers' Price Index (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Exhibit of the Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company. Lorain, Ohio - The Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company - Average Annual Earnings - Lorain Dock (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Exhibit of the Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company. Lorain, Ohio - The Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company - Percentage of Increase, Hourly Rates of Pay - Lorain dock (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Exhibit of the Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company. Lorain, Ohio - The Toledo, Lorain and Fairport Dock Company, Lorain, Ohio - Consist of Crews (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Memorandum of The Cleveland Stevedore Company (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Exhibit of the Cleveland Stevedore Company - Average Earnings of Huron Regular Dock Employees (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Exhibit of the Cleveland Stevedore Company - Comparative Wage Rates, 1945-1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Exhibit of the Cleveland Stevedore Company - Productive versus Nonproductive Time (Box 1, Folder 22)